Guide to the Robert Kraushaar papers, [ca. 1970-1990]
Kraushaar, Robert papers
- [no author provided] Analysis of Investments as at March 1981. Sheffield, England: City of Sheffield, 1981., March 21, 1981; Document (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Data on government investment decisions. 1 page
- South Yorkshire Country Superannuation Fund. Can We help Your Business Succeed?. South Yorkshire, England: South Yorkshire County Superannuation Fund, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Brochure (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Brochure describing the fund and its policies. 6 pages.
- [incomprehensible name]. Superannuation Fund Investments. South Yorkshire, England: City Council, 1981., November 5, 1981; Letter (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Letter to M Barratt Brown of Northern College answering enquiries about the Superannuation Fund Investments. 1 page
- Northern College, [no author provided] Occupational Pension Funds. Stainborough, England: Northern College, 1981., November 1, 1981; Research Paper (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Research paper on occupational pension funds. 5 pages
- [no author provided] [Title page missing]. 1984., October 1, 1984; Research Paper (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Research paper on women's experience working for the Council. Attached interview plans, case studies, and appendix for research terms. Title page and author mssing. 64 pages
- Employment Co-ordinator for Sheffield Employment Committee. The Development of Innovation and Technology Resources in Sheffield. Sheffield, England: Employment Programme Committee, 1984., November 19, 1984; Document (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Report to New Technology and Product Development Panel summarizing initiatives in last two years and future proposals for technology development. From the Employment Department. 5 pages
- Chief Personnel Officer, Sheffield. Sheffield Apprenticeship Training Project. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1984., November 9, 1984; Document (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Memo to the Training and Development Panel of the Personnel Services Sub-committee describing the Powell House Training Project. Attache detailed outline of project. 5 pages
- Darwin, John. Co-ordinating Group. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1983., May 9, 1983; Document (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Proposals for decision making roles in the co-ordinating group of the Employment Department. 2 pages, 2 copies
- [no author provided] Sheffield's Budget. Sheffield, England: [unknown publisher], c. 1983., c. 1983; Document/Article (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Photocopied article describing budget changes in the Sheffield City Council. Unclear as to the source of the document. 4 pages
- [no author provided] Not Just a Question of Numbers. Sheffield, England: Sheffield City Council, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Document (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Brief descriptions of City Council's attempts to stimulate economy, create jobs, and provide job training. Document contains some handwritten notes in margins. 3 pages
- Green, Geoff. Employment Plan. Sheffield, England: Central Policy Unit, 1987., 9-Jan-87; Document/Memo (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Memo to City Councillors Blunkett and Jackson. Outline of employment plan. Attached handwritten outline. 4 pages
- [no author provided] Employment Department: An Outline for the First Year. Sheffield, England: City of Sheffield, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Document (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Official city-produced outline of planned investment, promotion, and research initiatives for Sheffield's economy. 10 pages
- Benington, John. Employment Department: Review of the Work in the First Year. Sheffield, England: City of Sheffield, 1983., May 1, 1983; Document (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Descriptive report on year's projects. 2 pages
- Benington, John. The Employment Manifesto for 1984. Sheffield, England: City of Sheffield, 1984., June 8, 1984; Document (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Notes on the implications of the Sheffield District Labour Party's employment manifesto for the Employment Department. 8 pages
- [no author provided] The Steely City on Seven Hills. Sheffield, England: The Sheffield Times Special Report, 1985., March 29, 1985; Newspaper (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Newspaper special report section on Sheffield. 2 pages. Attached photocopy. 5 pages
- Benington, John. Employment Department: An Initial Outline. Sheffield, England: City Council, [no date provided]., January 1, 1982; Document (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Outline of objectives and proposals for job generation. 31 pages
- Sheffield City Council. Services in Sheffield. Sheffield, England: Central Policy Unit Sheffield City Council, 1984/5., 1984/5; Booklet (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Booklet for citizens of Sheffield describing policy for a wide range of social services. 48 pages
- Sheffield City Council. Services in Sheffield. Sheffield, England: Central Policy Unit Sheffield City Council, 1982/3., 1982/3; Booklet (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Booklet for citizens of Sheffield describing policy for a wide range of social services. 19 pages
- Sheffield City Council. Services in Sheffield. Sheffield, England: Central Policy Unit Sheffield City Council, 1986/7., 1986/7; Booklet (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Blunkett, David. Beitrag. Konferenz, Oberhausen, 1988., November 28, 1988; Research Paper (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Paper describing the role of community dynamic and democracy on local economy. 10 pages
- Coulson, Andrew. Employment Department: Checklist of Work in Progress. Sheffield, England: City of Sheffield, 1982., June 1, 1982; Document (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Outlines of objectives for each programme by the Employment Department for economic development. Attached documents by Cromar, Darwin, and Garrish. 15 pages
- Employment Programme Committee. Outlook Report 1990-93. Sheffield, England: Employment Programme Committee, 1990., July 23, 1990; Document (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Report of international and national context of economic development in Sheffield. Attached table of comparative economies: UK and international. 5 pages
- City of Sheffield Employment Despartment. Contracting Industry? Contract Compliance and the Building Industry. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1984., September 1, 1984; Bound Document (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Bound report of the 'Contracting Indistry?' Conference. 48 pages
- Lawless, Paul. Partnership in Urban Regeneration and Local Economic Development; The Case Stidy of Sheffield;UK. Sheffield, England: School of Urban and Regional Studies, Sheffield City Polytechnic, 1990., September 1, 1990; Academic research paper (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Academic paper, case study. 15 pages
- Blunkett, David. Towards a Social Policy. Sheffield, England: Sheffield City Council, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Document (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Paper examining the difference between social policy and social services. Critiques lack of government-populace partnerships. 3 pages
- Garnett, Nick. Sheffield's socialism loosens up. Sheffield, England: Financial Times, 1986., January 21, 1986; Newspaper article (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Photocopied newspaper article on City Council's actions. 1 page
- Gwyther, Matthew. Reforcing the Steel City. Sheffield, England: The Independent Magazine, 1988., October 1, 1988; Magazine article (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Photocopied magazine article on Sheffield's economic shifts. 5 pages
- Sheffield City Council: Department of Employment and Economic Development. The Uncertain Future of Special Steels. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, 1987., c. 1987; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Pamphlet on trends in the steel industry in Sheffield, the UK, and European Special Steels Industries. 20 pages
- Bentley, Gill. Jobs Rise Benefits South. Sheffield, England: Sheffield Unemployment Bulletin, 1988., Jamuary 1, 1988; page from bulletin (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Page from bulletin with unemployment trend charts. 1 page
- [no author provided] Employment Factsheet. Sheffield, England: City of Sheffield Employment Department, 1981., Jamuary 1, 1981; Document (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Report on employment trends in Sheffield. Source is Census. 3 pages
- [no author provided] Sheffield Science Park. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Official pamphlet for the public describing the new science park. Color images and diagrams. 1 page
- [no author provided] Sheffield Vision. Sheffield, England: Sheffield Development Office, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Official pamphlet for the public describing visions for housing, technological, business, and tourism initiatives. 1 page
- [no author provided] Sheffield Technology Park. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Official pamphlet for the public describing the new technology park. 1 page
- [no author provided] Mini Guide - Sheffield. Sheffield, England: English Tourist Board, 1981., c. 1981; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Pamphlet with maps and tourist attractions. 1 page
- [no author provided] Sheffield - Putting you in the picture. Sheffield, England: Sheffield City Council, 1980-86., c. 1980; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Pamphlet documenting the actions for social services City Council took in the face of government financial cutbacks. 43 pages
- [no author provided] Healthy Cities - Sheffield Targets. Sheffield, England: Sheffield Health Planning Team, 1987., c. 1987; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Pamphlet describing targets of World Health Organization for the population. 1 page
- [no author provided] The Jobs Jigsaw - Sheffield's Approach. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, 1987., February 1, 1987; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Pamplet describing developments in job availability. 23 pages
- [no author provided] [no title provided]. Sheffield, England: Sheffield City Council, 1984., December 19, 1984; Document (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Brief strategy and aim of city council to create employment opportunities. 2 pages
- Foster, Klemm, Woodward. Sheffield into the Eighties: A study of the Local Labour Market. Sheffield, England: Sheffield City Polytechnic Department of Economics and Business Studies, 1983., February 1, 1983; Report (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Analysis of trends in labor market. 59 pages
- Ward, David. The Pursuit of Fame and Fortune, and Social Usefulness. Sheffield, England: The Guardian, 1986, May 12, 1986; Photocopied newspaper article (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Special report section of newspaper on Sheffield. Photocopied. 2 copies 2 pages
- Caudrey, Adriana. Talent Corner. Sheffield, England: New Society, 1988., May 13, 1988; Photocopied newspaper article (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Photocopied newspaper article on a new Culture Indistry Quarter in Sheffield. 2 pages
- Lawless, Paul; Ramsden, Peter. Land Use Planning and the Inner Cities - The Case of the Lower Don Valley, Sheffield. Sheffield, England: Sheffield City Poltyechnic Local Government Studies, 1990., January/February 1990; Academic article (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Academic article. 14 pages
- [no author provided] A Guide to the Department. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, 1986., c. 1986; Document (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Decriptions of Department actions and strategies. 10 pages
- [no author provided] Review of council's organisation and management. Sheffield, England: City Council, 1983., February 1983; Document (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Memo to all city employees with attached diagrams of departmental organisation. 8 pages
- Barker, I.W.. Review of the Council's Organisation and Management. Sheffield, England: Sheffield City Council, 1983., January 31, 1983; Document (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Memo from Director of Environmental Health in response to debate on department organisation. 2 pages
- Coulson, Andrew; Darwin, John; Garrish, Norma. Checklist of Work in Progress. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1982., June 1982; Document (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Describes specific department programmes. 15 pages
- [no author provided] City of Sheffield Job Description. Sheffield, England: Employment and Economic Department, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Document (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Job Descriptions: Assistant Directors of Employment and Economic Development Department. 2 pages
- Blunkett, David; Macfarlane, Richard. The Third Way. Sheffield, England: New Socialist, 46, 68, 1987., February 1987; Photocopied magazine article (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Article analyizing workers' coops. 3 pages
- [no author provided] Sheffield Economic Development Map. Sheffield, England: Sheffield Development Office, 1988., c. 1987; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Maps of industrial areas. 1 page
- [no author provided] Report to Employment Programme Committee. Sheffield, England: Department of Land and Planning, Employment Department, 1984., December 3, 1984; Document (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Describes functions of Sheffield Technology Campus. 18 pages
- multiple. Sheffield Survey 1987. Sheffield, England: Financial Times, 1987., March 13, 1987; Newspaper article (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Section of times with articles on job generation and loss in Sheffield. 3 page
- Alcock, Phil; Lee, Phil. Struggles in the Welfare State. Sheffield, England: Critical Social Policy, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Journal article (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Analysis of welfare sector, 'socialist republic of South Yorkshire'. 20 pages
- [no author provided] Support for the Music Economy and the Unemployed in Sheffield. Sheffield, England: City Council, 1984., July 1984; Report (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Report on outcomes and further potential for the Municipal Music Services Project. 40 pages
- Clark, Nick; Critchley, Roger; Hall, David; Kline, Roger; Whitfield, Dexter. The Sheffield Council Jobs Audit - Why and How? Sheffield, England: Local Economy Magazine, 1987., February 1987; Journal article (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Report and analysis of Sheffield city council economic projects. 21 projects
- [no author provided] Product Development Scheme. Sheffield, England: Sheffield City Council, 1986., September 1986; Flyer (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Flyer describing ways to apply for funds to support manufacturing schemes. 1 page
- [no author provided] Trade Waste. Sheffield, England: Sheffield Council, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Flyer (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Explains ways in which Sheffield has expanded waste management services. 1 page
- [no author provided] Privatisation of Council Services. Sheffield, England: Local Government Information Unit of City Council, c. 1985-6, 1985-86; Bound Document (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Report describing provatisation of social services and the effects involved. 37 pages
- [no author provided] Employment Department Resource Plan for 1985/86. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1983., April 20, 1983; Document (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Outline of plans for projects. 4 pages. Attached employment trends and changes in the steel industry. 12 pages
- [no author provided] Action on Jobs and Services - Conference Reports. Sheffield, England: Central Policy Unit, 1983., July 1, 1983; Document (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Notes from conferences, attendance records, decisions. 11 pages
- [no author provided] Rent Grant Scheme. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Describes rent grant scheme for independent firms. Lists conditions, and qualifications. 2 pages
- [no author provided] Employment Department Staff Meeting Agenda. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1982., June 25, 1982; Document (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Meeting agenda. Attached draft of points of discussion. 3 pages
- Jackson, Helen. Employment Policy - Report to Labor Group. Sheffield, England: City Council, 1984., November 27, 1984; Document (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Report, critique of Employment Department. 2 pages
- Jackson, Helen; Machin, Steve. Contracting Industry? Contract Compliance and the Building Industry. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1983., c. 1983; Document (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Describes the development of City Council's Contracts Policy. 11 pages
- A Proposal to Create 1000 Jobs in Sheffield. Sheffield, England: [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Document (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Describes planned programmes for employment. Includes diagrams. 8 pages
- [no author provided] We Don't Want a City Built on Slave Labor. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Flyer (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Proclaims trade union rights, health and safety rights. Series of posters with color images. 8 pages
- Blunkett, David. Options for the Future for Maintaining Services, Jobs, and Local Control. Sheffield, England: City Council, 1985., June 27, 1985; Document (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Past developments supplemented by options and recommendations for future attention to the Labour Group. 5 pages
- [no author provided] Sheffield Vision to the Year 2000. Sheffield, England: [no publisher provided], [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Document (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Bulleted list of goals and methods for employment. 2 pages
- [no author provided] Employment Programme Committee - Review of the work in the first year of the Employment Department. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1983., June 1983; Report (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Full report of year's work. 90 pages
- Hayman, Keith. Community Business/Employment. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1984., September 13, 1984; Document (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Memo to councillors describing problems with community enterprises. Attached documents, diagram. 5 pages
- Hayman, Keith. Sheffield - A Case Study in Economic Regeneration. Sheffield, England: City Council, 1990., September 1990; Document (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Review of changes in local state government centrality. 4 pages
- [no author provided] Sheffield 2000 - Working Together for a Renewed City. Sheffield, England: Sheffield Economic Regeneration Committee, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Pamphlet for citizens describing networks in which Sheffield will develop new policy to face the future. 1 page
- [no author provided] Technology Resources for Industry in Sheffield. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, 1985., c. 1985; Public Booklet (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Booklet featuring technology centers in Sheffield. Color photos. 15 pages
- [no author provided] Exploding the Myths about Rates. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development,[no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Campaign action pamphlet explaining the cuts in grants from the central government to Sheffield. 1 page
- [no author provided] Forward into the 1990s - A Partnership with the Community. Sheffield, England: City Council, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Pamphlet describing specific neighborhood resources and projects. 2 pages
- [no author provided] Women in Sheffield - In Work, Out of Work. Sheffield, England: City Council, 1983., March 1983; Photocopied leaflet (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Photocopied leaflet "hightlighting the problems Sheffield women face in employment and unemployment"
- multiple. Special Report in Sheffield 1988. Sheffield, England: The Times. 1988., March 24, 1988; Newspaper section (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Front page section of newspaper with articles on Sheffield. 2 pages
- [no author provided] Product Development Scheme. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Pamphlet describing scheme to regenerate the manufacturing base in Sheffield. 1 page
- [no author provided] Product Development Service. Sheffield, England: Sceptre, Sheffield City Polytechnic Polylink, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Pamphlet describing services provided by Sceptre. 1 page
- [no author provided] Red Tape Recording and Rehearsal Studios General Information. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development Public Sector Development Team, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Pamphlet with information on facilities at recording studio. 3 pages
- [no author provided] Sheffield City Council Contracts Policy. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1984., September 1, 1984; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Pamphlet describing contracting policies for building and civil engineering. 1 page
- [no author provided] Cultural Industries Quarter. Sheffield, England: City Council, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Describes potential cultural centers in Sheffield, possibilities for job regeneration. 1 page
- [no author provided] Employment Services. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1983., May 5, 1983; Document (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Dicussion papers and programme descriptions for new employment services. 44 pages
- [no author provided] Statistical Profile 1984. Sheffield, England: City Council, 1984., c. 1984; Booklet (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Booklet with graphs of worker trends. 15 pages
- [no author provided] Sheffield in the 80's - A Strategy for Industry and Jobs. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1985., c. 1985; Booklet (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Strategy descriptions for the public. 15 pages
- Hopkins, Brenda. Sheffield City Council - The Economic Strategy. Sheffield, England: Department of Employment and Economic Development, Bound Document (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Report on programmes, initiatives, and specific projects. 27 pages
- [no author provided] Employment in Sheffield 1971-81. Sheffield, England: [no publisher provided], 1981., c. 1981; Document (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Count of employees in each sector of employment. 3 pages
- Benington, John. Employment Department - A Three Year Resource Plan to Meet Changing Needs. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1984., September 26, 1984; Document (Box 2, Folder 15)
  List of tasks for upcoming years. Charts attached.7 pages
- [no author provided] Support for Sheffield's Unemployed. Sheffield, England: Sheffield Unemployed and Drop-in Centres, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Booklet (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Booklet for the public with contact information for social service centres. 12 pages
- Benington, John. Sheffield - The Second Slump. Sheffield, England: Sheffield Trades Council, 1982., c. 1982; Booklet (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Booklet of collection of reports on the impact of government policy on employment. Workers' union documents.
- Child, Dave; Paddon, Mick. Sheffield: Steelyard Blues. Sheffield, England: Marxism Today, 1984., July 1, 1984; Magazine article (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Analysis of of Sheffield's labour movement. 5 pages
- Sharples, Adam. The New Local Economics: A Reply to John Benington. Sheffield, England: [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Article (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Analytical article. 5 pages
- Benington, John; Alcock, Pete; Cochrane, Alan; Lee, Phil. Struggles in the Welfare State - A parable of how things might be done differently. Sheffield, England: Critical Social Policy, 1983., September 29, 1983; Article (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Discussion with members of the Employment Department. 17 pages
- [no author provided] Sheffield Technology Campus - Presetation Summary. Sheffield, England: Sheffield City Council, 1985., February 1, 1985; Bound Document (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Official descriptions of Technology Campus. Appendix on specific programs. 45 pages
- Jackson, Helen. Economic Development - The Structure of Activity. Sheffield, England: Employment Department, 1988., February 26, 1988; Document (Box 2, Folder 16)